The original idea I had when I wanted to
create my first car was to also prove it
on a race car.
>> [music]
>> The GT1 class was built around
road-going supercars, evolving some of
the world's most iconic performance
vehicles into purpose-built race cars.
>> [music]
>> Welcome to Silverstone and the GT1
racing round two around this amazing
track. This is racing at its finest,
right, James?
>> So, the original CCGT was very much a
skunkworks Koenigsegg project. We didn't
have a big budget [music] for it. So, we
had a skeleton crew led by one of our
top engineers, Doug Belenius, who really
was a genius and had a knack of figuring
things out, reading the regulation, and
also doing the craftsmanship himself
[music]
with only two, three people helping him
converting the chassis, the bodywork of
the CC8S and CCR into the CCGT.
Unfortunately, right when we had
finished the car, they shut down the
series.
>> Today, November 6th, 2011, marks the end
of an era. What a race, ladies and
gentlemen, the final GT1 World
Championship.
>> And as a celebration of this effort, I'm
very proud and excited to introduce
>> the Koenigsegg CCGT1.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Oh.
>> The downforce numbers are really up
there with the highest we've ever
achieved, and that's of [music] course
based on a shape of car that we
originally conceived at the end of the
'90s for the first CC8S.
>> Elevated with our optional track
package.
>> Racing suit, helmet, [music] wheels with
slicks, different brake pad materials,
different adjustments to the shock
absorbers.
>> Incorporating a motorsport developed
pneumatic air jack system.
>> The track pack also features a carbon
fiber roll cage.
>> Engineered to enable efficient
conversion from road [music] to track
use.
>> The CCGT1 features the biggest rear
[music] wing we've ever made. What's
different from the original race car?
It's actually active.
>> [music]
>> In front of the rear wing, a new
five-inlet roof scoop feeding air to the
engine while also providing cooling for
the light speed transmission and
dampers.
With modern emissions regulations
eliminating the option for twin [music]
quick fuel fillers,
this area has been redesigned with
graphical readouts for fuel and oil
pressure levels for easy pit [music]
crew monitoring.
>> You can also see a slightly wider stance
[music]
than the CC850. The wheel arches are a
little bit flared.
>> [music]
>> On top of that, we have pushed our air
core technology
>> [music]
>> to the maximum, making a retro-style
looking racing [music] three-spoke
hollow carbon fiber wheel.
>> Optimized air core technology, combined
with a new internal structural wall that
increases strength while reducing
weight, makes this one of our lightest
carbon fiber wheels ever.
>> It's very much Koenigsegg thinking in a
nutshell from my perspective.
>> The cockpit [music] has been redesigned
with a series of track focused
enhancements.
An all new ESS sequential shifter
inspired [music] by the original
developed for the CCGT.
>> Ambience of a race car with a race car
kind of switches.
>> Placing greater emphasis [music] on
driver control, functionality, and
performance.
A brand [music] new mechanical drive
mode selector. Auto, sequential, manual,
and reverse. [music]
Four modes, one movement.
Introducing
the Chrono Cluster 3. Designed to keep
the driver fully informed with complete
visibility of the [music] car's vital
systems. And also our analog G-Force
meter seamlessly integrated.
>> [music]
>> In addition to the sequential shifter,
[music]
the CCGT1 features an optional six-speed
gated ESS manual.
>> And I remember for the first time
driving it first on our airfield, then
on Hockenheim in Germany, it was just
the most exciting thing I've ever
driven. And it's something that never
left my mind. So having the opportunity
to relive this experience now [music]
for our customers to experience on the
track, on the road, is just unbelievable
[music] and so truly exciting to me and
the team.
Very much looking forward to getting
these cars out [music] into the field
and being experienced.